<!-- Copyright (c) 2012 by Subset Games. Modification developed by Matt Alioto. All rights reserved -->

<!--   
			SUMMARY  - 
A list of all main events to be called by lists
	does not include sub-events)
	
Structure:
	START_BEACON_ZOLTAN
	STORE_ZOLTAN
	NOTHING_ZOLTAN
	
Item:	
	ZOLTAN_FREE_AUGMENT
	ZOLTAN_FREE_MAP
	ZOLTAN_ODD_MOON   (ZOLTAN_ODD_MOON_CHEK)
	
Hostile:
	ZOLTAN_FIGHT
	ZOLTAN_PIRATE
	ZOLTAN_MANTIS
	ZOLTAN_ENGI

	
Neutral:
	ZOLTAN_LIFERAFT  (ZOLTAN_LIFERAFT_HIRE)
	
Environmnt:
--->

<!-- Event ideas --
Boarder "wink and nod"
Sophon diplomat
Pilgrim diplomat
Science - investigate Sower
-->



<eventList name="HOSTILE_ZOLTAN">
	<event load="ZOLTAN_FIGHT"/>
	<event load="ZOLTAN_PIRATE"/>
	<event load="ZOLTAN_MANTIS"/>
	<event load="ZOLTAN_ENGI"/>
	<event load="ZOLTAN_ASTEROID"/>
	<event load="REBEL"/>
	<event load="REBEL_AUTO"/>
</eventList>

<eventList name="NEUTRAL_ZOLTAN">
	<event load="ZOLTAN_LIFERAFT"/>
	<event load="ZOLTAN_SCIENCE_DOCK"/>
	<event load="ZOLTAN_RIFT_FIGHT"/>
	<event load="ZOLTAN_CREW_SCAN"/>
	<event load="FRIENDLY_SLAVER"/>
	<event load="PIRATE_BRIBER"/>
	<event load="ASTEROID_EXPLORE"/>	
</eventList>

<eventList name="ITEM_ZOLTAN">
	<event load="ZOLTAN_FREE_AUGMENT"/>
	<event load="ZOLTAN_FREE_MAP"/>
	<event load="ZOLTAN_ODD_MOON"/>
	<event load="FIND_DRONE"/>
	<event load="FREE_ITEMS"/>
	<event load="FUEL_FOR_DRONE"/>
	<event load="REFUEL_STATION"/>
	<event load="REPAIR_STATION"/>
	<event load="TRADER_CIV"/>
</eventList>

<eventList name="BOARDERS_ZOLTAN">
	<event load="ZOLTAN_BOARDERS"/>
	<event load="ZOLTAN_BOARDERS_MANTIS"/>
	<event load="BOARDERS_HACKING"/>
</eventList>

<eventList name="DISTRESS_BEACON_ZOLTAN">
	<event load="ZOLTAN_DISTRESS_MANTIS"/>
	<event load="ZOLTAN_DISTRESS_SHELL"/>
	<event load="DISTRESS_SATELLITE_DEFENSE"/>
	<event load="DISTRESS_STATION_FIRE"/>
	<event load="FRIENDLY_BEACON"/>
	<event load="TRAP_BEACON"/>
	<event load="STRANDED_BEACON"/>
</eventList>

<eventList name="QUESTS_ZOLTAN">
	<event load="ZOLTAN_TRADE_HUB"/>
	<event load="ZOLTAN_QUEST_PRIMITIVES"/>
	<event load="FEDERATION_PLANET_SIGNAL"/>
	<event load="QUEST_MANTIS_INVASION_START"/>
	<event load="QUEST_CREWDEAD_START"/>
</eventList>

<eventList name="NEBULA_ZOLTAN">
	<event load="NEBULA_ZOLTAN_ROCK"/>
	<event load="NEBULA_ZOLTAN_EYE"/>
	<event load="STORM_ZOLTAN_SUPPLY_CHOICE"/>
	<event load="NEBULA_EMPTY"/>
	<event load="NEBULA_EMPTY"/>
	<event load="NEBULA_REBEL"/>  
	<event load="NEBULA_AUTO"/>
</eventList>


<!-----------
		STRUCTURE!!!
	Requred structural 
------------>

<event name="START_BEACON_ZOLTAN">
	<text load="START_BEACON_ZOLTAN"/>
</event>
<textList name="START_BEACON_ZOLTAN">
	<text>You've entered Sophon territory. They have not yet recognized the Pilgrims as an independent nation, but they've cast a blind eye towards the resistance in the past.</text>
	<text>The Sophon patrol their borders but let you pass when you ID as Pilgrim. Let's hope they won't be so courteous to the United Empire.</text>
	<text>You arrive in Sophon space. From what you have heard they remain politically neutral, unwilling to risk alienating the Pilgrims or the powerful United Empire.</text>
	<text>You're far from Pilgrim home space here in Sophon territory, and it's not clear whether the authorities will have any goodwill remaining. Still, you have to push forward.</text>
</textList>

<event name="STORE_ZOLTAN">
	<text load="STORE_ZOLTAN"/>
	<store/>
</event>
<textList name="STORE_ZOLTAN">
	<text>The IHTG has set up a joint shop with a group of Sophon machinists. Although it is difficult to tie most Sophon down to a single trade, these are mere engineers and applied scientists, and likely have little opportunity elsewhere in Sophon society.</text>
	<text>This planet, a backwater otherwise, is known as one of the more capitalist areas in Sophon territory. Here, you can find Sophon who condenscend to haggle, trade, and build equipment for profit rather than fun.</text>
	<text>A faint IFF signature - a private encryption scheme. A small team of Mantises (Mantii?) has hunkered down on a small moon. They're selling goods, which were obtained illegally as a matter of course. This being bat country, you don't want to stop here; if they've just come off a fresh kill, though, you may get an honest trade.</text>
</textList>

<event name="NOTHING_ZOLTAN">
	<img back="BG_BORING" planet="NONE"/>
	<event load="NOTHING_ZOLTAN_EVENTS"/>
</event>

<eventList name="NOTHING_ZOLTAN_EVENTS">
	<event>
		<text>This sector is crowded with Sophon vessels. A light asteroid field is entering the atmosphere of a nearby planet - a fireworks show on a galactic scale. Beautiful.</text>
		<choice hidden="true" req="energy">
			<text>Talk to your Sophon crewmember</text>
			<event>
				<text>"This is a typical Sophon vacation spot - some of them are admiring this event, while others are relaxing by performing scientific measurements on it."</text>				
			</event>
		</choice>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>The Sophon military is holding an exercise near this beacon: symmetrical adversary tactics. Weapons crackle and spit across the impressive Sophon shield systems. They use their advanced beam lasers to cut through the outer shielding shell, then demolish the remaining layers with fearsome pulse lasers. Impressive tactics, to be sure - but would they work in a real war?</text>
		<choice hidden="true" req="energy">
			<text>Talk to your Sophon crewmember</text>
			<event>
				<text>"I've read about this ancient Human game - 'pule'? All the predictive trigonometry and physics in the galaxy won't help you predict the ball's path after a few bounces. War is the same way; it cannot be reduced to calculated maneuvers and risk management. You Humans have always been better at that sort of fuzzy thinking."</text>				
			</event>
		</choice>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>There's a Sophon ship waiting near this beacon; you hail them, but it ignores your hails and jumps away shortly afterwards. They can be an aloof race.</text>
		<choice hidden="true" req="energy">
			<text>Talk to your Sophon crewmember</text>
			<event>
				<text>"No reason to be offended, they just didn't feel compelled to answer."</text>				
			</event>
		</choice>
		<choice hidden="true" req="human">
			<text>Talk to your Human crewmember</text>
			<event>
				<text>"Eh, they get like this. Took a few years to get used to it after we made first contact. It's hard to be mad at them; when they DO talk to you, they're nice enough."</text>				
			</event>
		</choice>		
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>A Sophon orbital research park is stationed at this beacon. You admire the beautiful architecture of the station, but its massive power signature makes you nervous. Time to move on.</text>
		<choice hidden="true" req="energy">
			<text>Talk to your Sophon crewmember</text>
			<event>
				<text>"Sophon have lost interest in boring old Electro-Weak theory research. This power signature indicates that the station is examining the nature of sub-Quantum phenomena; much juicier stuff." He pauses for a moment before remarking, "Yes. 'Juicy'. Such a delightful word! Human language is nearly as colorful as ours."</text>
			</event>
		</choice>
	</event>	
	<event>
		<text>A message broadcast from a nearby planet announces the presence of an ancient Sophon university available for visiting. Likely just a tourist trap, but still too bad you don't have the time to visit.</text>
		<choice hidden="true" req="energy">
			<text>Talk to your Sophon crewmember</text>
			<event>
				<text>She turns up her nose. "This old place? They haven't published any fun research for decades."</text>
			</event>
		</choice>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>You have to admit - Sophon space is a beautiful and peaceful place indeed. However, re-engaging the FTL and finishing your mission is your priority, not sight-seeing. You wonder if Sophon are ever nostalgic for their homeworld.</text>
		<choice hidden="true" req="energy">
			<text>Talk to your Sophon crewmember</text>
			<event>
				<text>"Nostalgia? I've lived with you Humans for a while now, but I still haven't figured that out. Intriguing. I have to agree, this sector is particularly aesthetically pleasing."</text>
			</event>
		</choice>
	</event>	
</eventList>

<!-----------
		DISTRESS!!!
	Beacons
------------>

<event name="ZOLTAN_DISTRESS_MANTIS" unique="true">
	<text>Your jump interrupts a Sophon security ship as it follows a Mantis pirate into an asteroid field. They message you, "This is a delicate matter - please, don't feel the need to assist."</text>
	<environment type="asteroid"/>
	<distressBeacon/>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Interfere and save the Mantis ship.</text>
		<event>
			<text>A 'delicate matter?' Something's up. You set off for the heart of the asteroid field and engage the Sophon there.</text>
			<ship load="ZOLTAN_SHIP_SAVE_MANTIS1" hostile="true"/>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Interfere and help the Sophon ship.</text>
		<event>
			<text>You overtake the Sophon and catch up with the Mantis ship in the asteroid belt. Humans and Mantis have been killing each other for decades, which makes it a tradition. You'll be damned if you'll buck position.</text>
			<environment type="asteroid"/>
			<ship load="ZOLTAN_SHIP_SAVE_MANTIS2" hostile="true"/>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Don't interfere.</text>
		<event>
			<text>The Sophon have their own agenda - best to leave them to it. You prepare to jump.</text>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>

<event name="ZOLTAN_DISTRESS_SHELL" unique="true">
	<text>You arrive to find an elegant Sophon yacht, all curves and flying buttresses, laying silent in space. You hail; no answer. The ship is abandoned. It's a mystery what happened to the crew, but it'd be a shame to let the opportunity go to waste.</text>
	<distressBeacon/>
	<autoReward level="RANDOM">standard</autoReward>
	
</event>
	
<!-----------
		QUEST!!!
	Beacons
------------>
	

<event name="ZOLTAN_TRADE_HUB" unique="true">
	<img back="PLANET_CLOSE" planet="NONE"/>
	<text>You come to a Sophon trade and supply hub - everything the weary traveller needs, provided they have the right documentation.</text>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Try to talk your way in.</text>
		<event load="ZOLTAN_TRADE_HUB_TALK"/>
	</choice>	
	<choice hidden="true" req="teleporter" lvl="1">
		<text>(Teleporter) Beam directly to the civilian deck.</text>
		<event>
			<text>You re-materialise in a dark corner of the main concourse and are able to conduct your investigations in peace.</text>
			<choice hidden="true">
				<text>Continue...</text>
				<event load="ZOLTAN_TRADE_HUB_SUCCESS"/>
			</choice>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true" req="energy">
		<text>(Sophon) Have your crewmember present his official documentation and pay the entry fee [ Dust: -10 ].</text>
		<event>
			<text>They scan ID that declares your crewmember an official citizen, collect their fee, and let you pass.</text>
			<item_modify>
				<item type="scrap" min="-10" max="-10"/>
			</item_modify> 
			<event load="ZOLTAN_TRADE_HUB_SUCCESS"/>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Leave.</text>
		<event>
			<text>You don't have the papers - well, the neuro-laced identity bracelets - to get in, so best not to try.</text>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>


<eventList name="ZOLTAN_TRADE_HUB_TALK">
	<event>
		<text>They don't see many of your species in these parts, and you stick out like a Casvagarian Sea Slug in a Plutonian Shrimp Stew. You make it back to the ship with a gang of Sophon guards in tow!</text>
		<ship load="ZOLTAN_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
		<boarders min="2" max="4" class="energy"/>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>You pose as traders and succeed in bypassing airlock security - however, it's only a matter of time before someone realizes your ID cards are counterfeit!</text>
		<choice hidden="true">
			<text>Continue...</text>
			<event load="ZOLTAN_TRADE_HUB_SUCCESS"/>
		</choice>
	</event>
</eventList>
<eventList name="ZOLTAN_TRADE_HUB_SUCCESS">
	<event>
		<text>You head into a ship supply store. It is a well-equipped, self-service affair. An order is dialled into a terminal, Dust is deposited, and the item is dispatched from a nearby chute.</text>
		<store/>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>You head into the cantina for gossip. Topics of conversation in the cantina range from crop distribution microbes to the joys of Slug pleasure cruises.</text>
		<choice hidden="true">
			<text>Continue...</text>
			<event>
				<text>You overhear one group discussing a newly discovered planet yet to have first contact, and note down its location.</text>
				<quest event="ZOLTAN_QUEST_PRIMITIVES"/>
			</event>
		</choice>
	</event>
</eventList>

<event name="ZOLTAN_QUEST_PRIMITIVES" unique="true">
	<text>You arrive at the primitive planet that you heard about at the cantina and are surprised to see a Sophon ship facing off against a United Empire warship.</text>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Continue...</text>
		<event>
			<text> You tap into their frequency and hear the UE captain yelling, "Your ethical integrity be damned, I have orders to establish diplomatic relations with these...these, uh..." You figure you have a few seconds to think while the captain looks up their name.</text>
			<choice hidden="true">
				<text>Interfere - make first contact with the primitive aliens.</text>
				<event>
					<text>The local people - furry, one-eyed tree lizard things - begin chanting when they see you. Suddenly the sky is lit by laser fire - the Sophon opened fire on your ship! You dash back to the shuttle and join the fight.</text>
					<ship load="ZOLTAN_PRIMITIVES_ZOLTAN" hostile="true"/>
				</event>
			</choice>
			<choice hidden="true" req="energy">
				<text>Ask your Sophon crewmember to defuse the situation</text>
				<event>
					<text>"I am conducting a research study on the differential between United Empire and Pilgrim Human conduct," your crewmember says to the Sophon captain, "Although it is lamentable to disturb the development of this race, we must prioritize research of the behavior of sentient races." It seems to have worked, and the Sophon move off. Naturally, the Empire warship attacks you immediately. What did you expect?</text>
					<ship load="ZOLTAN_PRIMITIVES_REBEL" hostile="true"/>
				</event>
			</choice>			
			<choice hidden="true">
				<text>Protect the aliens' way of life - Attack the United Empire ship.</text>
				<event>
					<text>These creatures should be left to develop at their own pace. You direct all weapons on the United Empire ship and begin the firing sequence.</text>
					<ship load="ZOLTAN_PRIMITIVES_REBEL" hostile="true"/>
				</event>
			</choice>
			<choice hidden="true" req="human">
				<text>Attack the United Empire ship, but insult them first.</text>
				<event>
					<text>"Tumhara matta chode hain! I am of you motherfucking loyalists in this motherfucking game! Yob tvoyu maht, nekulturniy suka! Go suck up a Mantis, you socialist panty-wasted scruffy-looking nerf herders!" You may not have accomplished much with your words, but damn if that didn't feel good.</text>
					<ship load="ZOLTAN_PRIMITIVES_REBEL" hostile="true"/>
				</event>
			</choice>			
			<choice hidden="true">
				<text>Leave.</text>
				<event>
					<text>You don't want to alert the United Empire of your presence and you don't want to anger the Sophon in their territory. The best solution is to leave.</text>
				</event>
			</choice>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>

<!-----------
		ITEM!!!
	Events that can give something ususally no fight
------------>
<event name="ZOLTAN_FREE_AUGMENT" unique="true">
	<text>A Sophon academy sits docked just outside the beacon perimeter. They're happy to show you the fruits of their labor, and offer something to take home with you.</text>
	<autoReward level="LOW">augment</autoReward>
</event>

<event name="ZOLTAN_FREE_MAP" unique="true">
	<text>The Sophon stationed near this beacon are happy to receive you. As they give you the formal tour of their ship you spy some local star charts and mentally log the details.</text>
	<reveal_map/>
	<ship load="ZOLTAN_SHIP" hostile="false"/>
</event>
	
<event name="ZOLTAN_ODD_MOON" unique="true">
	<text>Something strikes you as odd about a moon in the distance.</text>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Check it out.</text>
		<event load="ZOLTAN_ODD_MOON_CHECK"/>
	</choice>
	<choice>
		<text>Leave it be.</text>
		<event>
			<text>You try not to fixate on the moon in the aft scanner and you set the coordinates for the next jump.</text>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true" req="BOARDER">
		<text>(Boarding Drone) Send a drone to probe the surface.</text>
		<event>
			<text>Initial scans indicate a network of caves not far underground. You launch a boarding drone and it breaks through the surface into the cavern below.</text>
			<item_modify>
				<item type="drones" min="-1" max="-1"/>
			</item_modify>
			<choice hidden="true">
				<text>Continue...</text>
				<event>
					<text>Your drone discovers a vast cave network and evidence of excavation. Buried deep below you find a Sophon scientist, still hard at work. She tells you that all her colleagues are long dead. You decide not to ask questions and offer to let her join your crew.</text>
					<crewMember amount="1" class="energy">Itania</crewMember>
				</event>
			</choice>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>

<eventList name="ZOLTAN_ODD_MOON_CHECK">
	<event>
		<text>A closer inspection reveals signs of habitation on the surface, but nothing else particularly interesting.</text>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>Sending a shuttle to explore a beckoning cave system you discover signs of a battle - and a still-functioning weapon!</text>
		<autoReward level="LOW">weapon</autoReward>	
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>A deep scan of the surface reveals a cave system that runs for miles, and what looks like a Dust reservoir left over from some heavy-duty construction.</text>
		<autoReward level="MED">scrap_only</autoReward>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>It looks as if a team could break through the fragile layer of the moon's surface into a hidden cavern.</text>
		<choice hidden="true">
			<text>Attempt to detonate some explosives to break through the surface. [ Missiles: -1 ]</text>.
			<event load="ZOLTAN_ODD_MOON_EXPLOSION"/>
		</choice>
		<choice>
			<text>You call this archeology? This is a job for a team of experts, not a warship. Let's get out of here.</text>
			<event/>
		</choice>
	</event>
</eventList>
	
<eventList name="ZOLTAN_ODD_MOON_EXPLOSION">
	<event>
		<text>A portion of the surface layer is destroyed in an impressive display, revealing miles of caves. You don't have time to fully explore them, but you find some remains of an old subterranean base that could be useful.</text>
		<item_modify>
			<item type="missiles" min="-1" max="-1"/>
		</item_modify>
		<autoReward level="RANDOM">scrap_only</autoReward>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>The explosives are set remotely, but the detonation achieves nothing. What a waste.</text>
		<item_modify>
			<item type="missiles" min="-1" max="-1"/>
		</item_modify>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>Your explosives reveal the 'cave' is actually a secret base, located in a network of bunkers just under the surface. Everyone inside is dead; some Mantis clearly came through here recently. It looks like the Sophon were researching advanced ship weaponry. You take one of their better examples back to your ship.</text>
		<autoReward level="RANDOM">weapon</autoReward>
		<item_modify>
			<item type="missiles" min="-1" max="-1"/>
		</item_modify>
	</event>
</eventList>
	
	
<!-----------
		HOSTILE!!!
	Events that call up a fight for sure
------------>
<event name="ZOLTAN_FIGHT">
	<img back="BACKGROUND" planet="NONE"/>
	<text load="ZOLTAN_FIGHT"/>
	<ship load="ZOLTAN_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
</event>
<textList name="ZOLTAN_FIGHT">
	<text>A Sophon ship makes contact. "The nature of the day is rotational. The fever is emaciated. The reason is-" They've caught some nasty deep space dementia. Before you can consider finding help for them, they open fire.</text>
	<text>You're surprised when a stationary Sophon ship opens fire. It appears there are aggressive pugilists even among the 'enlightened'.</text>
	<text>You receive a message, "This area is off limits. Submit your ship to processing." It's only one guard ship in a lonely beacon. You decide to fight your way out.</text>
	<text>You discover a number of Sophon civilian ships fighting off pirates. Unfortunately one ship mistakes your purpose and moves in to attack! Their communications have been shot out; you have no choice but to fight.</text>
	<text>Like many areas in Sophon space, the residents of this sector prepared well for Galactic war. The military here seem to have given up reasoning with foreigners, preferring instead to attack on sight!</text>
	<text>A Sophon ship is waiting at this beacon. They request your identification, but radiation from the sun in this system is disrupting your communications. They take your silence for aggression and move in to attack.</text>
	<text>The Sophon ship patrolling this area hails you: "This area is off limits. Secrecy is vital." They power their weapons.</text>
	<!-- Add more! -->
	
</textList>

<event name="ZOLTAN_PIRATE">
	<img back="BACKGROUND" planet="NONE"/>
	<text load="ZOLTAN_PIRATE"/>
	<ship load="PIRATE" hostile="true"/>
</event>
<textList name="ZOLTAN_PIRATE">
	<text>"Emergency, all ships in range, we are under attack!" The frequency matches a nearby Sophon ship; you move in on their pursuer. They take your intervention as a cue to jump away. Cowards.</text>
	<text>You jump just in time to witness a Sophon ship's FTL drive overload. In his final moments their captain implores you not to get involved, but it's too late - their attacker is already upon you!</text>
	<text>Despite their precautions, pirates have begun to harass the local Sophon settlements across this sector. One such pirate spots your ship and moves in to attack.</text>
	<text>A ship with pirate markings demands your surrender. It is sad times when even Sophon space is beset by pirates. You doubt these fools will be missed.</text>
	<text>You spot a pirate ship looting a small Sophon cruiser. They spot you and move in to attack before your FTL drive has a chance to recharge.</text>
	<!-- Add more instead of repeating ! -->
	
	<text>"Emergency, all ships in range, we are under attack!" The frequency matches a nearby Sophon ship; you move in on their pursuer. They take your intervention as a cue to jump away. Cowards.</text>
	<text>You jump just in time to witness a Sophon ship's FTL drive overload. In their final moments they implore you not to get involved, but it's too late - their attacker is already upon you!</text>
	<text>Despite their precautions, pirates have begun to harass the local Sophon settlements across this sector. One such pirate spots your ship and moves in to attack.</text>
	<text>A ship with pirate markings demand that you surrender. It is sad times when even Sophon space is beset by pirates. You doubt these fools will be missed.</text>
	<text>You spot a pirate ship looting a small Sophon cruiser. They spot you and move in to attack before your FTL drive has a chance to recharge.</text>
</textList>

<event name="ZOLTAN_MANTIS" unique="true">
	<text>You pick up the last broadcast from a rupturing Sophon freighter. A calm voice states: "Mantis attack highly effective; 87 percent chance of terminal reactor-" You're interrupted by fire off the port bow!</text>
	<ship load="MANTIS_FIGHT" hostile="true"/>
</event>

<event name="ZOLTAN_ENGI" unique="true">
	<text>You jump into a debris field that used to be a small Sophon vessel. Sensors warn that its putative attacker - an Engi combat craft - has locked weapons on you. You suspect one of the false-flag attacks which Mantis are notorious for, but the details are unimportant with the ship fast bearing down on you.</text>
	<ship load="ENGI_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
</event>


<event name="ZOLTAN_ASTEROID" unique="true">
	<text>You arrive in an asteroid field and are greeted by a Sophon guard. "This is a highly strategic area," he hisses, "The Empire has spies everywhere. Do you have any idea what could happen if they catch us allowing a Pilgrim warship to transit here? We're going to have to detain you." You don't have time for this.</text>
	<environment type="asteroid"/>
	<ship load="ZOLTAN_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
</event>


<!-----------
		NEUTRAL!!!
	Events that could have a fight
------------>

<event name="ZOLTAN_LIFERAFT" unique="true">  <!-- ALSO A QUEST!!-->
	<img back="DEEP_SPACE" planet="NONE"/>
	<text>You pick up a Sophon life raft floating in deep space. Its inhabitant asks you to retake her ship from the pirates who recently commandeered it. "It is, of course, critical," she concludes, "that you not destroy my vessel in the process."</text>
	<ship load="ZOLTAN_LIFERAFT" hostile="false"/>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Engage the pirates.</text>
		<event>
			<ship hostile="true"/>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice>
		<text>Leave.</text>
		<event>
			<text>You refuse to get her ship back, but still offer to drop her off at the next station. She is incensed, but directs you to a nearby starbase just the same.</text>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>
<eventList name="ZOLTAN_LIFERAFT_HIRE">
	<event>
		<text>She responds haughtily, "Friend, I'm a doctor, not a resistance fighter. I'm not cut out for this space hero business."</text>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>She thinks for a moment before looking you in the eye. "Any opportunity to..." she smiles, "...perform research on such a remarkable Human specimen." Is she coming on to you?		
		</text>
		<item_modify>
			<item type="scrap" min="-40" max="-40"/>
		</item_modify>
		<crewMember amount="1" class="energy">Yesmin</crewMember>
	</event>
</event>

	
<event name="ZOLTAN_SCIENCE_DOCK" unique="true">
	<img back="DEEP_SPACE" planet="NONE"/>
	<text>In a sector of deep space, what appears to be a Sophon science ship requests permission to dock.</text>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Dock with them.</text>
		<event load="ZOLTAN_SCIENCE_DOCK_LIST"/>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Have them keep their distance.</text>
		<event>
			<text>They leave without a word.</text>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>	
<eventList name="ZOLTAN_SCIENCE_DOCK_LIST">
	<event>
		<text>You allow them to approach, but are caught unaware when they open fire!</text>
		<ship load="ZOLTAN_SCIENCE_DOCK" hostile="true"/>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>"We have been studying your little secession movement, and determined that the "Pilgrims" have potential to be a net positive for the galaxy. Please accept this gift to aid your journey.</text>
		<autoReward level="MED">stuff</autoReward>
	</event>
</eventList>


<event name="ZOLTAN_RIFT_FIGHT" unique="true">
	<img back="WORMHOLE" planet="NONE"/>
	<text>You come to a quiet part of Sophon space and encounter an ancient Sophon professor who has managed to do inspeakable things with every Sophon's favorite tool, the particle accelerator. He has opened a wormhole; he is, of course, quite mad. Batshit insane. Most likely tenured. And quite brilliant, actually; he hails you quoting Shakespeare and demanding a pound of flesh. As you are disinclined to comply with his request, he asks for something else: your beliefs regarding the Endless.</text>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>"They were wise."</text>
		<event>
			<text>"They lost sight of what they didn't know! Their arrogance grew with their power!" The wormhole pulses and a confused, angry Mantis ship hurtles toward you!</text>
			<ship load="ZOLTAN_RIFT_MANTIS" hostile="true"/>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>"They were powerful."</text>
		<event>
			<text>"Even unlimited power was not enough to save the Endless - nor will it save you, Pilgrim!" His crazed cackling rings in your ears. The wormhole opens up, and seconds later a Slug ship is attacking from the other direction!</text>
			<ship load="ZOLTAN_RIFT_SLUG" hostile="true"/>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>"They were Gods."</text>
		<event>
			<text>"Aha, a Pilgrim!" he cackles, "Gods, you say. But in strange aeons, even gods may die!" The wormhole contracts, then expands - a Sower ship appears with guns blazing. It appears they were in combat when they were thrust across space-time.</text>
			<ship load="ZOLTAN_RIFT_ROCK" hostile="true"/>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>
<event name="ZOLTAN_RIFT_SUCCESS">
	<text>You emerge victorious, and once again a hologram of the Sophon appears on your bridge. He is smiling. "With wisdom, with power, with humility, you may avoid the mistakes of your ancestors. You may achieve what us, their children, may only dream of." The wormhole snaps shut, leaving a glittering halo of Dust. The Sophon gestures before cutting the transmission - as if to say "take what you will".</text>
	<autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
</event>

<event name="ZOLTAN_CREW_SCAN" unique="true">
	<img back="BACKGROUND" planet="NONE"/>
	<text>You arrive at a Sophon security checkpoint set up in a perimeter around the beacon. "As per recent agreement with the United Empire, we need to screen your ship for Pilgrim fugitives."</text>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>You don't have time for this nonsense. Attack!</text>
		<event>
			<text>Expecting resistance, their Energy Shield is raised and ready for combat.</text>
			<ship load="ZOLTAN_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Submit to profiling.</text>
		<event load="ZOLTAN_CREW_SCAN_LIST"/>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true" req="slug">
		<text>(Slug Crew) Have your Slug talk them into letting you go.</text>
		<event>
			<text>You give the guards permission to dock with the ship, but before they come on board your crew member slowly advances to meet them. As far as you can tell no words were exchanged, but the guards offer you some supplies and say the ship checks out. Best to not ask questions.</text>
			<autoReward level="MED">fuel_only</autoReward>
		</event>
	</choice>			
</event>
<eventList name="ZOLTAN_CREW_SCAN_LIST">
	<event>
		<text>The Sophon security staff board your ship and scan the crew's faces into a computer. You can't help but feel nervous as they come towards you. To your surprise, the security officer winks at you and scans a nearby bulkhead instead. "No fugitives here! You may go, Captain."</text>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>The Sophon security staff board your ship and begin scanning the crew's faces into a computer. Suddenly alarms go off and the Sophon leap on one of your crew! "This person is wanted for parking like an asshole and mounting a rear spoiler on a front-engined ship! Surrender them to us!"</text>
		<choice hidden="true">
			<text>Give up your crew member.</text>
			<event>
				<text>It's a tough call, but Sophon law holds sway here. Besides, that one always seemed a bit...shifty.</text>
				<crewMember amount="-1"/>
			</event>
		</choice>
		<choice hidden="true">
			<text>Refuse and fight.</text>
			<event>
				<text>You're not going to leave anyone behind. You pull away from the station with the enemy guards on board. Unfortunately, they are able to sabotage your weapon system in the chaos. It's time to leave!</text>
				<ship load="ZOLTAN_CREW_SCAN" hostile="true"/>
				<boarders min="2" max="4" class="energy"/>
				<status type="divide" target="player" system="weapons" amount="2"/>
			</event>
		</choice>
	</event>
</eventList>
			
<!-----------
		NEBULA!!!
	Events with unique environments
------------>
<event name="NEBULA_ZOLTAN_ROCK" unique="true">
	<img back="BG_NEBULA" planet="NONE"/>
	<text>At the center of this nebula, a small Sower vessel is mining materials from a metallic asteroid. It seems to identify you as hostile, and opens fire!</text>
	<environment type="nebula"/>
	<ship load="ROCK_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
</event>

<event name="NEBULA_ZOLTAN_EYE" unique="true">
	<img back="NEBULA" planet="PLANET_UNPOPULATED_SMALL"/>
	<text>Inside this nebula you detect a rogue planet drifting through space, on its surface a huge monolith visible at this distance even to the naked eye. A Sophon professor hails you from the planet. "Ah, I'm glad you're here! I am curious how this monolith will respond to Human stimulus."</text>
	<environment type="nebula"/>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Pull the ship in closer.</text>
		<event load="NEBULA_ZOLTAN_EYE_LIST"/>
	</choice>
	<choice>	
		<text>Leave.</text>
		<event>
			<text>Your mission is to save the resistance, not discover new wonders around the galaxy. You prepare to jump.</text>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>
<eventList name="NEBULA_ZOLTAN_EYE_LIST">
	<event>
		<text>As you approach, an ancient alien voice speaks to you: "Your mission has brought you great battles, and great losses. This will help ease the pain." A few minutes later someone reports medical equipment has appeared on the ship!</text>
		<weapon name="BOMB_HEAL"/>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>You approach the planet and wait, but nothing happens. The Sophon hails: "Disappointing. The builders of this artifact must not recognize that which was in them, in you. You must accept their judgement."</text>
		<ship load="ZOLTAN_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>You approach the planet carefully, trying to keep your ship from breaking up in orbit. The monolith, whatever it is, must sense as much because the next thing you know you have enough Dust to patch up your damage and more besides!</text>
		<autoReward level="HIGH">scrap_only</autoReward>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>As you approach, a kaleidoscope of colours fills the view-screen and one of your crew begins to age rapidly in reverse, eventually disappearing into nothingness. Let's hope they've transcended physical existence, and not just been forced out of it.</text>
		<crewMember amount="-1"/>
	</event>
</eventList>

<event name="STORM_ZOLTAN_SUPPLY_CHOICE" unique="true">  <!-- can also use this with other sectors?-->
	<img back="NEBULA" planet="NONE"/>
	<text>You spy two pirate ships lurking in the nebula here. They remain unaware of your presence; you're able get your scanners to at least identify their cargo: One is carrying the fuel supplies, the other the ammunition. They begin to drift away from each other in the storm.</text>
	<environment type="storm"/>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Secure the fuel supply.</text>
		<event>
			<text>You jet toward the pirate with the fuel supplies and engage - hopefully you can leave the ship in one piece!</text>
			<ship load="STORM_PIRATE_SUPPLY_FUEL" hostile="true"/>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Secure the ammunition.</text>
		<event>
			<text>You jet toward the pirate with the ammunition and engage - hopefully you can leave the ship in one piece!</text>
			<ship load="STORM_PIRATE_SUPPLY_AMMO" hostile="true"/>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Let them leave.</text>
		<event>
			<text>Sometimes discretion is the better part of valour. </text>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>

		
<!-----------
		BOARDERS!!!
	Events with boarder calls
------------>

<event name="ZOLTAN_BOARDERS" unique="true">
	<text>"You never should have come here - your presence endangers the entire Sophon race! Some Sophon's tolerance of you Pilgrims risks ending years of friendship between us and the United Empire. Your secession, your life, are not worth our peace. Prepare to defend yourselves!"</text>
	<ship load="ZOLTAN_SHIP" hostile="true"/>
	<choice>
		<text>Continue...</text>
		<event>
			<boarders min="3" max="4" class="energy"/>
		</event>
	</choice>	
	<choice hidden="true" req="teleporter">
		<text>(Teleporter) "Prepare to suck vacuum!" Beam the boarders off your ship.</text>
		<event/>
	</choice>	
</event>

<event name="ZOLTAN_BOARDERS_MANTIS" unique="true">
	<text>The Mantis outcasts sometimes make the mistake of taking the Sophon for easy game, which may explain their presence in this normally peaceful sector. A Pilgrim ship is a much more attractive target, however. A scout moves in to attack while a boarding party beams aboard from a nearby transport!</text>
	<ship load="MANTIS_FIGHT" hostile="true"/>
	<choice>
		<text>Continue...</text>
		<event>
			<boarders min="2" max="3" class="mantis"/>
		</event>
	</choice>	
	<choice hidden="true" req="teleporter">
		<text>(Teleporter) Beam 'em into space. Pop goes the Mantis.</text>
		<event/>
	</choice>	
</event>

<!-----------
		SPECIAL!!!
	-
------------>

<event name="ZOLTAN_PEACE_QUEST" unique="true">
	<text>An unarmed Sophon transport vessel is slowly making its way toward the beacon here. They hail: "This is a Sophon peace envoy. We carry no weapons or shielding and rely on the mercy of others to communicate our message."</text>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Attack them.</text>
		<event load="ZOLTAN_PEACE_QUEST_ATTACK"/>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Hear them out.</text>
		<event>
			<text>They continue. "We take your silence for interested contemplation." They talk at length about quantum uncertainty and fate, but either it's beyond your simple mind or it's all nonsense.</text>
			<choice hidden="true">
				<text>Continue...</text>
				<event>
					<text>They finish: "Please, spread the word of enlightenment to those that have not heard. Once you have, contact our brethren." They transmit coordinates of their so-called "brethren".</text>
					<quest event="ZOLTAN_PEACE_QUEST2"/>
				</event>
			</choice>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Leave.</text>
		<event>
			<text>The galaxy is at war - there's no time for talk of peace. You leave their hails unanswered and charge the jump drive.</text>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>


<eventList name="ZOLTAN_PEACE_QUEST_ATTACK">
	<event>
		<text>You charge your weapons - not that this will take much.</text>
		<ship load="ZOLTAN_PEACE_QUEST_ATTACK1" hostile="true"/>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>Just as you're preparing to attack you detect a nearby jump signature. A Sophon defense ship comes to their aid!</text>
		<ship load="ZOLTAN_PEACE_QUEST_ATTACK2" hostile="true"/>
	</event>
</eventList>

<event name="ZOLTAN_PEACE_QUEST2">
	<img back="EXCITING" planet="NONE"/>
	<text>You arrive at the location specified by the peace-loving Sophon, but the only thing nearby is a United Empire ship, closing in fast! "We've found you! You're not getting away this time!"</text>
	<ship load="REBEL" hostile="false"/>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Attack.</text>
		<event>
			<text>You power your weapons and prepare to fight.</text>
			<ship hostile="true"/>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Attempt to hail them.</text>
		<event>
			<text>They open communications: "I can't imagine there's anything you could say that will save you. You bastards should never have betrayed humanity."</text>
			<choice hidden="true">
				<text>"Is it too much to ask to allow us to govern ourselves in peace?"</text>
				<event>
					<text>"Secession is treason. You think this could end any way but war?"</text>
					<choice hidden="true">
						<text>"The galaxy is huge, you can build your Empire elsewhere and leave us to ourselves."</text>
						<event>
							<text>"No! We will not allow you to shatter the United Empire just for the sake of your little cult!" They charge.</text>
							<ship hostile="true"/>
						</event>
					</choice>
					<choice hidden="true">
						<text>"True progress can only be achieved when we are willing to accept that which is not ourselves."</text>
						<event>
							<text>Suddenly all indications of the loyalist ship fade away and a Sophon fleet appears around your ship. The captain of the ship you met previously materializes on your bridge.</text>
							<choice hidden="true">
								<text>Continue...</text>
								<event>
									<text>"Although your methods are crude and most certainly ineffective, it is clear you took our previous meeting to heart. If your actions are indicative of Pilgrim ideals, we shall do what we can to aid in their fight."</text>
									<unlockShip id="7">A Zoltan cruiser has been unlocked and added to the hangar!</unlockShip>
									<autoReward level="HIGH">weapon</autoReward>
								</event>
							</choice>
						</event>
					</choice>
				</event>
			</choice>
			<choice hidden="true">
				<text>"Surrender. Your ultimate destruction is inevitable. We've left scores of loyalists destroyed in our wake."</text>
				<event>
					<text>They shut off communications and immediately engage.</text>
					<ship hostile="true"/>
				</event>
			</choice>
			<choice hidden="true">
				<text>"Your damned jingoism is causing millions of deaths! The United Empire is an evil one, and Human nationalism is the root of evil in the modern galaxy!"</text>
				<event>
					<text>"Spreading humanity throughout the stars is our manifest destiny. You have forgotten who you are - I, for one, am still proud to be human!" They charge.</text>
					<ship hostile="true"/>
				</event>
			</choice>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>


<event name="ZOLTAN_SURRENDER">
	<text load="ZOLTAN_SURRENDER"/>
	<choice>
		<text>Accept their offer.</text>
		<event>
			<ship hostile="false"/>
			<autoReward level="RANDOM">stuff</autoReward>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice>
		<text>We will not accept surrender!</text>
		<event/>
	</choice>
</event>

<textList name="ZOLTAN_SURRENDER">
	<text>"Yes, yes, you've demonstrated your species' capacity for violence quite extensively, well done. If we reward your efforts will you bother someone else?"</text>
	<text>The enemy ship hails; the vidscreen shows their bridge showered in sparks from malfunctioning equipment. Iit's safe to assume they're trying to surrender. Accept their offer?</text>
	<text>Communications report that the Sophon are broadcasting on all frequencies. The captain appears on screen and says, "Yes, I am not surprised, your species hardly looks enlightened. Fine. Take what you wish."</text>
	<text>The Sophon captain hails and mutters something about the border patrol force catching up with you someday; you're more interested in his offer of surrender.</text>
	<text>"We assumed that your species intelligence was directly proportional to your brute strength. We yield."</text>
	<text>"You have bested us. If only your species' efforts were put to use improving the galaxy rather than your military might."</text>
	
	<!-- duplicate for now -- add more?-->	
	<text>"Yes, yes, you've demonstrated your species' capacity for violence quite extensively, well done. If we reward your efforts will you bother someone else?"</text>
	<text>The enemy's power signature suddenly ceases, save for a weak, repeating signal - it's safe to assume they're trying to surrender. Accept their offer?</text>
	<text>Communications report that the Sophon are broadcasting on all frequencies. The captain appears on screen and says, "In the face of superior force, acquiescence is only...logical. Take what you require."</text>
	<text>The Sophon captain hails and mutters something about the border patrol force catching up with you someday; you're more interested in his offer of surrender.</text>
	<text>"We assumed that your species intelligence was directly proportional to your brute strength. We yield."</text>
	<text>"You have bested us. If only your species' efforts were put to use improving the galaxy rather than your military might."</text>
</textList>