<!-- Copyright (c) 2012 by Subset Games. All rights reserved -->

<!--   
			SUMMARY  - 
A list of all main events to be called by lists
	does not include sub-events)
	
Structure:
	
Hostile:
	
Neutral:
	
Environmnt:

--->


<eventList name="NEUTRAL_ROCK">
	<!--<event load="ROCK_NURSERY"/>-->
	<!--<event load="ROCK_ZOLTAN_HELP"/>-->
<!--
	<event load="ROCK_MANTIS_HUNTER"/>
	<event load="ROCK_MANTIS_FREIGHTER"/>
	<event load="ROCK_ATHIEST"/>
	<event load="ROCK_LOOTING"/>
	<event load="ROCK_STARSHIP_MINE"/>
	
	<event load="PIRATE_CIVILIAN"/>
	<event load="MERCENARY"/>
	<event load="FRIENDLY_SLAVER"/>	
	<event load="ASTEROID_DERELICT_SHIP"/> 
	-->
</eventList>

<!--
<eventList name="BOARDERS_ROCK">
	<event load="ROCK_BOARDERS_SHIP"/>
	<event load="ROCK_BOARDERS_ASTEROID"/>
	<event load="ROCK_BOARDERS_SUN"/>
</eventList>

<eventList name="HOSTILE_ROCK">
	<event load="ROCK_SHIP"/>
	<event load="ROCK_PIRATE"/>
	<event load="ROCK_FIGHT_ASTEROID"/>
	<event load="ROCK_PIRATE_ASTEROID"/>
	<event load="ROCK_PIRATE_SUN"/>	
</eventList>

<eventList name="DISTRESS_BEACON_ROCK">
	<event load="FRIENDLY_BEACON"/>
	<event load="TRAP_BEACON"/>
	<event load="STRANDED_BEACON"/>
	<event load="PIRATE_CIVILIAN_BEACON"/>
	<event load="CIVILIAN_ASTEROIDS_BEACON"/>  
	<event load="REBEL_VS_FEDERATION"/> 
	<event load="ESCORT_BEACON"/>
	<event load="DISTRESS_TRAPPED_MINER"/>
	<event load="DISTRESS_INFESTATION"/>
	<event load="DISTRESS_SATELLITE_DEFENSE"/>
	<event load="DISTRESS_STATION_FIRE"/>
	<event load="DISTRESS_STATION_DISEASE"/>
</eventList>


<eventList name="NEBULA_ROCK">
</eventList>

<eventList name="QUESTS_ROCK">
	<event load="ROCK_QUEST_MARRIAGE_START"/>	
	<event load="QUEST_ESCORT"/>
	<event load="FEDERATION_PLANET_SIGNAL"/>
	<event load="MERCENARY_WORK_START"/>
	<event load="QUEST_CREWDEAD_START"/>
</eventList>
-->
<!-----------
		STRUCTURE!!!
	Requred structural 
------------>
<event name="START_BEACON_ROCK">
	<text load="START_BEACON_ROCK"/>
</event>
<textList name="START_BEACON_ROCK">
	<text>The Sower rarely interact with other races unless it's necessary to complete their sacred mission to prepare the universe for the return of the Endless. Let's hope they don't construe your travel here as interference.</text>
	<text>The Sower are a robot race whose secrets remain a mystery. It is not unheard of to have a peaceful journey through their lands - but don't count on it.</text>
</textList>

<event name="STORE_ROCK">
	<text load="STORE_ROCK"/>
	<store/>
</event>
<textList name="STORE_ROCK">
	<text>You cross paths with a Sower vessel returning from a rare diplomatic mission. Equally surprising, they are remotely pinging your ship's inventory system.</text>
	<text>You come across a Sower colony. It's rare they deal with outsiders, but they need raw materials from offworld.</text>	
	<text>With the local Sower settlements unwilling to communicate with other life forms, an opportunistic Mantis crew has postponed its piracy activities and set up shop to catch any passing trade.</text>
	<text>The Sower interact with few races, but even they seem to respect the wisdom of the Sophon - a few of them have established a trading post in the husk of an abandoned capital ship.</text>
	<text>You receive a hail on Pilgrim frequencies; a large colony running metastrategic subroutines seemed to have decided to trade with you.</text>
</textList>

<event name="NOTHING_ROCK">
	<text load="NOTHING_ROCK"/>
</event>
<textList name="NOTHING_ROCK">
	<text>You receive a message meant to degrade you as aliens. You half expect an attack but it seems to have come from a small civilian shuttle.</text>
	<text>No one bothers your ship as you float among numerous space stations and mining platforms. The Sower certainly run efficient operations.</text>
	<text>You arrive and detect signs of battle. A few ships are taking passes at each other near a small station. You don't know if it's a territory issue, a contest or a rite of passage but you decide it's best to stay out of it.</text>
	<text>There's not much at this beacon. Just a few abandoned depots, stripped clean.</text>
	<text>A few Sower logistics vessels pass by but they ignore all communications. Must not be in their programming.</text>
	<text>You see a small trading post and hail them, but there is only silence."</text>
	<text>You see a Sophon merchant and ask about his wares. He responds, "Sorry, but it took years to gain their trust. I can't be seen communicating with you. I hope you understand." He cuts communications.</text>	
</textList>

